Michael Van Le

Full Stack Developer

Michael Van Le - New York, NY - Email: <u>le.michael.v@gmail.com</u> Phone: 646-535-8706 LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelvanle/</u> Github: <u>https://github.com/miketocoding/</u> Portfolio: <u>https://miketocoding.github.io/</u>

I've recently completed the software engineering immersive at General Assembly and am excited to bring my skills, curiosity, and analytical nature to any team. My experience in public service, working for the City of New York, helped to hone my astute attention to detail, allowed me to problem solve collaboratively, and work within tight timelines. I look forward to continuing my growth as a developer and adding my skills and enthusiasm to future teams.

Technical skills

Full-stack software development: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Mongoose, Express, Django, MongoDb, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, Agile methodologies

Experience

Freelance Software Engineer

July 2021 - Present

- Orange Wellness, Remote, August 2, 2021 August 16, 2021
 - Built a frontend web application to improve equity and access to mental healthcare in rural areas.
 - o Technologies used: React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Proxies, Git, GitHub.
 - Collaborated with a team of 1 other software engineer, 1 project manager, and 3 UX/UI designers.

Software Engineering Fellow, *General Assembly, Remote*

April 2021 - July 2021

- Full time 500+ hour, 12 week Software Engineering Immersive training program focused on full-stack web development using a variety of modern programming languages and technologies. Select projects:
 - Memory Lane | Personal Travel Blog
 - Full-stack application with RESTful backend API.
 - Technologies used: React, JavaScript, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub.
 - Beets by Dwight | eCommerce store for purchasing produce
 - Full-stack application with RESTful backend API.
 - Technologies used: React, JavaScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub.
 - Emotion Tracker: It's healthy to feel | Emotion tracking application for children
 - Full-stack application with Restful backend API.
 - Technologies used: JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDb, Mongoose, Express, Git, GitHub.

Job Opportunity Specialist, Human Resources Administration, City of New York, NYC December 2015 - April 2021

- Interviewed and processed over 75 cases weekly.
- Assessed client eligibility for public assistance: Cash Assistance, Medicaid, SNAP.
- Worked with clients to remove barriers to employment and made referrals to employment programs.

Activities Coordinator & Swim Instructor, Central Queens YM & YWHA, NYC Nov 2010 - Dec 2015

- Scheduled private swim lessons for a team of 25 swim instructors and instructed students aged 2 70 years.
- Created and presented weekly progress reports to the aquatics director.

Education

Master of Science in Information Systems, Baruch College Zicklin School of Business, New York, New York 2014 Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Economics, St. Lawrence University, Canton, New York 2010